<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bella&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bella&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://bunbobabe.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://bunbobabe.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About the Movie</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Movie Details Director Patricia Cardoso Screenplay George LaVoo and Josefina López Based on the play Real Women Have Curves by Josefina Lopez Distribution Newmarket Films Production LaVoo Productions Release Date 2002 Run Time 1:26:21 minutes Budget $3M Box Office $7.7M Movie Overview + Reception Real Women Have Curves is a coming-of-age drama-comedy adapted from the play &amp;ldquo;Real Women Have Curves&amp;rdquo; written by Chicana playwright Josefina López. The film spotlights the young protagonist, Ana García—a Chicana teenager and recent high school graduate living in Eastern Los Angeles, California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahora le toca a ella</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_2/</guid>
      <description>Later in the evening after the graduation party, Ana’s mom and dad are shown discussing her college education privately in their bedroom. The dad is shown displaying open-mindedness to the idea of Ana going to college whereas Ana’s mom is obstinately against the idea. Carmen goes on a brief spiel in Spanish, saying [translated] “I can educate her. I can teach her to sew. I can teach her to raise her kids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ana gets into Columbia</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_7/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, Mr. Guzman comes to Ana’s house to tell her she has gotten into Columbia with a full scholarship. Ana is elated, but her parents are dismayed when they find out Columbia is in New York City, all the way across the country. Mr. Guzman does his best to convince the parents to let her go, saying “you left your country for a better opportunity. And now it’s Ana’s turn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ana’s first day in Estella’s factory</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_3/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, Ana comes to work at Estella’s factory for the first time. Ana begins to admire one of Estella’s dresses, to which her mom remarks “You’ll never fit into that one. It’s a size 7” (00:13:31). Two workers in the factory, Norma and Panchita, enter and are introduced to Ana. Carmen makes a fat-shaming comment to Panchita, which is poorly received. In general, the atmosphere in the factory and between the workers is tense, hostile, and unfriendly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can’t you see she’s bigger than the cake?</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_1/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, Ana comes back from her last day of high school to see that her family has thrown her a surprise graduation party. Ana’s dad offers her some cake, to which Ana’s mother, Carmen, replies [translated], “can’t you see she’s bigger than the cake?” in Spanish (00:007:28). This is the first of a slew of body-shaming remarks that the mom makes against Ana’s weight and body shape. The parents then ask Ana why she quit her job at a fast food restaurant, which viewers saw in a previous scene, and the mom says Ana will come to work in her sister, Estella’s, dress-making factory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difundiendo chismes</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_5/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, Carmen is shown initiating chismes with the other factory workers about Norma. It was revealed in a previous scene that Norma had to leave the factory because she was moving back to Mexico to get married. Her two sisters and mother—who also worked in the factory—were moving back to Mexico with her, causing Estella to lose four seamstresses and dress production to greatly slow. While gossiping, Carmen says that Norma’s fiancé convinced her to have sex with him the night before the wedding, and the following day, the fiancé never showed up to the ceremony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guiding Questions</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/guiding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/guiding/</guid>
      <description>Why does Ana’s mother, Carmen, not think Ana needs to go to college, despite her teacher Mr. Guzman insisting that she is very gifted and bright? What is the importance of the chismes or gossip that the women at Estella’s factory engage in? Do you think it is helpful, harmful, or a bit of both? Carmen is constantly shown making body-shaming comments about Ana’s appearance throughout the movie. How does this influence how Ana perceives herself and beauty in general?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Latina Girlboss (?) Mrs. Glass</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_6/</guid>
      <description>Because Estela has lost four seamstresses and is behind on dress production, she is struggling to pay the electricity and rent bills for the factory. Estela is shown emailing Mrs. Glass, the owner of the manufacturing company that buys Estella’s dresses and sells them at Bloomingdale’s, to ask for an advance on the payment for the dresses. Ana is bewildered, asking why Estela is emailing her instead of going to see Mrs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/references/</guid>
      <description>output: html_document bibliography: references.bib nocite: &amp;lsquo;@*&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scene 10: Stretch marks, cellulite, and real women</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_10/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, the women of Estela’s factory are close to completing a big dress order. Exasperated by the hot and suffocating conditions of the factory, Ana takes her shirt off to cool down. Carmen immediately disparages her appearance, telling her she looks awful. Estela, Pancha, and Rosalí come to Ana’s defense, telling her she looks beautiful. Each woman begins to talk about her own insecurities, such as her cellulite, stretch marks, and fat and in doing so, starts to strip off her clothes to show the others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scene 11: Ana goes off to college</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_11/</guid>
      <description>In this final scene, Ana is preparing to go to the airport to head to New York City. She has already received support for her decision from the whole family besides her mom. Ana speaks to her mom through her locked door, asking her to please come outside and give her blessing to Ana. Carmen is shown deliberating in her room, pacing back and forth and looking at Ana’s photo dejectedly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scene 8: Cigars and Condoms</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_8/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, Ana goes to the pharmacy to pick up a cigar for her grandfather and also decides to buy condoms for the first time. She later goes over to Jimmy’s house when his parents aren’t over, and she initiates sex with Jimmy—her first time. Before they begin, Ana asks him to turn on the lights, saying “I want you to see me,” drawing his attention to her naked body which has been the subject of ridicule from her mother throughout the movie (01:04:14).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scene 9: Don’t eat the flan!</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_9/</guid>
      <description>Here, Ana and Carmen are in a restaurant after finishing at the doctor’s office. Throughout the movie, Carmen had insisted to Ana that she was pregnant although Ana never took her seriously. At the doctor’s, he confirms that Carmen is not pregnant but is undergoing “el cambio de vida,” or menopause, to her incredulity and disbelief. At the restaurant white eating a flan, Carmen has finally wrapped her head around it, saying “I’m no longer a woman…A grandmother is what I should be at this age” (1:07:18).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The San Antonio statue</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_4/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, Carmen is shown hanging up a San Antonio statue for Ana. She reveals she also hung one up for Estela 11 years ago when she first turned 18. The statues are importantly shown hanging upside down. This brief snippet showcases the influences of Catholicism in Latin American culture and folklore. Saint Anthony of Padua is known as a miracle worker who helps people find things they’ve lost. When hung upside down, he is invoked to quell issues with love and romance and help people leave singlehood.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
