<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sexuality on Bella&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/tags/sexuality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sexuality on Bella&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://bunbobabe.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://bunbobabe.github.io/tags/sexuality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Difundiendo chismes</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_5/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, Carmen is shown initiating chismes with the other factory workers about Norma. It was revealed in a previous scene that Norma had to leave the factory because she was moving back to Mexico to get married. Her two sisters and mother—who also worked in the factory—were moving back to Mexico with her, causing Estella to lose four seamstresses and dress production to greatly slow. While gossiping, Carmen says that Norma’s fiancé convinced her to have sex with him the night before the wedding, and the following day, the fiancé never showed up to the ceremony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scene 8: Cigars and Condoms</title>
      <link>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bunbobabe.github.io/posts/post_8/</guid>
      <description>In this scene, Ana goes to the pharmacy to pick up a cigar for her grandfather and also decides to buy condoms for the first time. She later goes over to Jimmy’s house when his parents aren’t over, and she initiates sex with Jimmy—her first time. Before they begin, Ana asks him to turn on the lights, saying “I want you to see me,” drawing his attention to her naked body which has been the subject of ridicule from her mother throughout the movie (01:04:14).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
